Sister!
Sister Gesang!
How dare you!
Swallowed by the Chilam Spider Lily of greatest desire.
I want to see how you
can save her.
No future tribulations.
No past lives.
We won't meet again in this life.
The Spider Lily stays parted.
If there is an afterlife,
I won't be
a pawn at the mercy of Heaven.
Sister!
High God,
I have completed my duty to find the sword.
I shall return to report.
Immortal,
you have great magical power.
Please save Sister Gesang!
I told you.
I only came down to the mortal realm to find the sword.
It is inconvenient for me to interfere with other matters.
It is the tribulation that the High God and this lady must overcome.
Saving people from suffering,
isn't that what immortals are supposed to do?
How can you divide it into someone's tribulation?
Everything in the world
has its own destiny
and its own tribulation.
If I interfere,
who knows if the future karma
will be even harder to bear?
A disgrace to our kind.
You have no talent.
Trash fallen from the sky.
And you still dare to dream of becoming an immortal.
You should just die.
You want to join us?
What right does a lowly tree demon have?
Get lost.
Otherwise, I'll chop off your roots to go with my wine.
She's a demon.
Beat her to death. Beat her to death.
Suppress.
Since the evil has taken root, what use are you?
What are you doing?
She has turned into a demon.
Before she fully awakens,
we must kill this tree demon to prevent future troubles.
Don't be soft-hearted.
Are you questioning my judgment?
I wouldn't dare.
Master,
you will save Sister Gesang,
right?
Tu Luohua's demonic power is extremely strong.
These demon flowers
have condensed countless resentful energy.
Trying to save her
is practically impossible.
With ordinary methods,
it's indeed hard to save her.
Master,
do you mean there is another way?
Master.
Sister Gesang is a good person.
Oh no,
a good demon.
She was just trying to save us
and got badly injured.
I beg you.
Please save my sister.
Sister!
This demonic aura
cannot be eliminated without Heavenly Thunder.
Heavenly Thunder?
If it strikes now,
wouldn't her soul be destroyed?
Take them to a safe place.
Bai Jingqing,
when hanging the bell on the plum tree,
once said,
A thought of longing can overcome the cold.
Today, this protective spiritual tree...
Why can't I redeem her?
Thunder spell.
Heavenly tribulation.
Master.
Don't move.
What is Master doing?
He is going to use the thunder spell
to redeem Gesang's demonic nature.
If Gesang directly receives this thunder spell,
she will surely turn to ashes.
He wants to use himself as a lightning rod
to bear most of the damage for her.
Can we
do anything to help him?
Help him?
Heavenly thunder is meant to punish immortals and demons.
You and I are both mortals.
Touching it means certain death.
Child.
Go check on her.
She's alive.
Sister Gesang is still alive!
Good.
It hurts.
Why does it hurt so much?
What happened to me?
Brother Qingxuan.
Sister Gesang,
Master saved you.
You were infected by Tu Luohua's demon flower.
Master drew the heavenly thunder
and used himself as a conductor
to eliminate the demonic nature in you.
Why
did you pay such a huge price to save me?
You said
if demons do evil,
you would never tolerate it.
You once said
that a tree's seed
wherever it lands,
it will take root and sprout.
I have guarded Sanshanliu
for hundreds of thousands of years.
I've seen countless truth-seekers
who, in order to become immortal,
are willing to give up all emotions and desires.
Only one person
was willing to give up the path to immortality
to keep a thought of longing.
The places she passed through
have a bit more vitality
than other places.
Just now,
when you saved that child,
you had no evil thoughts in your heart.
You sacrificed yourself to save all living beings,
and so did I.
That's all.
Thank you for saving me, High Immortal Qingxuan.
I, Gesang,
cannot repay you.
Why does my body
feel a little strange?
You were injured by the heavenly thunder.
It is already not easy
to keep you alive.
I...
I lost all my magic power.
It is already very hard
to keep your human form.
I know a place
with a spiritual spring
that can revive dead trees.
Whether it can help you regain your demonic power
depends on whether you
are willing to take root in this world again.
If you want,
follow me.
Although we had your help,
we eliminated the four great demons
and wiped out Tu Luohua's lair.
No matter how you look at it,
it's quite a heroic feat, right?
Grandmaster,
I, Hu San,
shall take my leave now.
Mr. Hu,
are you sure you won't come with us?
The road ahead is dangerous.
It'd be safer if we traveled together.
As you know,
I was sent by His Majesty.
Now that the great demon of Tushan has been eliminated,
I must announce it to the world.
Besides,
I have to escort Miss Yezi home.
If fate allows,
we shall definitely meet again.
You care for the common people
and save them from suffering.
I hope you keep this original intention.
Given time,
you will surely achieve greatness.
Thank you for your guidance, grandmaster.
Feilu.
Learn well from my grandmaster.
Cultivate your mind
and your magic.
If there's a chance in the future,
you can come work at the Directorate of Astronomy.
I'll pass.
I want to follow my master,
roam the world with my sword,
and uphold justice.
Okay.
Miss Gesang,
then I wish you and grandmaster
a speedy
recovery.
Recovery.
Farewell.
Sister Gesang.
You were injured by heavenly lightning.
How did you recover so quickly?
Could it be
that you were struck into lightning wood?
You need a beating.
Just kidding.
However,
this matter is indeed strange.
You were injured by heavenly lightning
and lost all your magic,
yet your energy recovered so quickly.
Indeed.
Right.
You mentioned before
that you fell from the sky.
That's what my mother told me.
Break!
I see.
What about you?
The road ahead is long
and extremely dangerous.
Are you sure you want to follow me?
Master,
don't even think about getting rid of me.
By the way, Master,
where are we going?
Qingqiu.
No matter where we go,
I will follow brother Qingxuan.
Let's go.
Master.
Who is in Qingqiu?
Is your family there?
None of your business.